# **BRIGHT WILLIAMS BOAKYE**

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER | LARAVEL, VUE JS DEVELOPER

Bwboakye@gmail.com, Bwboakye@outlook.com, +233 241-849-088, Ghana

## PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

A Self-motivated and dedicated Software Engineer with outstanding skills and **6 years of experience** in software development; web application development, website development and web service development. Possess excellent communication skills and interpersonal relationship skills and is able to work independently and as part of productive team to meet demanding deadlines and product excellent solutions.

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

**Senior Software Engineer Makis Technologies** (December 2022 – Date)

#### **Duties**

Design, develop, and implement high-quality software solutions, adhering to coding standards and best practices to meet project requirements and deadlines.

Lead and participate in the entire software development lifecycle, including requirements analysis, design, coding, testing, debugging, and deployment.

Collaborate with cross-functional teams, including product managers, designers, and other developers, to define project scope, features, and deliverables.

Write clean, efficient, and well-documented code, ensuring robustness and maintainability for ongoing development and future enhancements.

Investigate and troubleshoot complex technical issues, applying analytical skills to identify root causes and implement effective solutions to minimize system downtime.

Lead by example in terms of work ethic, technical excellence, and collaboration, fostering a positive and innovative team environment.

Collaborate with user experience and design teams to implement user-friendly interfaces and ensure seamless interaction between software components.

Participate in technical discussions, present findings, and communicate complex technical concepts to both technical and non-technical team members.

Lead Software Engineer – Bisa Technologies (January 2022 – November 2022)

**Duties -** Leading software development department in designing and developing solutions

Developing of website, web applications

Lead training sessions for clients

Integrating third party applications and APIs Server setup and maintenance

Database setup and maintenance

Preparing of Technical Requirement Documents

Project management and supervision

# **Software Engineer – Bisa Technologies** (January 2021 –December 2021)

**Duties -** Developing of website, web application

Integrating third party applications and Apis

Server setup and maintenance

Database setup and maintenance

Ensuring code standard compliance by the team

Lead daily standup

Development of application technical document

## Backend Developer - FundiHub IT Company (January 2019 - January 2021)

**Duties** – Writing well designed, testable and efficient code using best software practices

Working closely with Frontend and Mobile developers on web applications projects

Maintaining, expanding and enhancing Web Applications/ websites built.

Integrate data from various back-end services and databases

#### IT/Systems Developer – Bernard and Associates Limited (December 2017- July 2018)

**Duties**: Development and management of MallGhana Ecommerce platform. (http://mallghana.com)

Management of company website (<a href="http://bernardnassociates.com">http://bernardnassociates.com</a>)

Servicing and troubleshooting of company computers

# IT Assistant - University of Ghana Computing Systems (National

## Service) September 2016 – November 2017

Duties: ICT lab management

Configuring, and troubleshooting System and network problems. Providing of assistance on usage of University Ghana Applications

Front Desk Service and Desktop Support

Management of active Directory and Email Systems

#### **EDUCATIONAL HISTORY**

Sep 2012 – May 2016	University of Ghana, Legon. http://:www.ug.edu.gh Bachelor of Arts in Computer Science with Economics
Oct 2008 – Aug 2012	Ghana Armed Forces Senior High Technical School, Kumasi WASSCE Certificate.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Web Application development using (PhP, Laravel, Vue Js, Node Js)
- Mobile Application development (Flutter, Dart)
- Website development (Html, CSS, JQuery, JavaScript, PHP, Ajax, bootstrap)
- Content Management System (WordPress)
- Desktop Application Development (VB.NET, C#.NET)
- Database Programming (MySQL, MsSQL, PostgreSQL)
- Project management using PRINCE2 Foundation (Certified) and SCRUM Methodologies Foundation (Certified)
- Linux commands, Git commands / GitHub / BitBucket

#### **TRAINEESHIP**

# **Maxim Nyansa IT Solutions**

July 2016 – August 2016

I was selected for an international organization to participate in a Seven Week Intensive training with the following focus Areas

Prince 2 (International Project Management), Professional Scrum Master (International Project Management), Software testing

Cross –Cultural Development, It infrastructure, It Architecture and Personal Development

#### PERSONAL COMPETENCIES

- Ability to work in a fast-paced environment to set deadlines
- Ability to work with team members in achievement of set goals
- Ability to work with less Supervision
- Excellent oral and written correspondence with an exceptional attention to details

# **COURSES IN PROGRESS**

DevOps for Absolute Beginners: Azure DevOps, Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, Terraform, Ansible - AWS, Azure & Google Cloud (Udemy)

## PORTFOLIO LINK

https://brightwilliamsboakye.com

## TOP PROJECTS WORKED ON

https://www.jinssavingsandloans.com/(Laravel web Application, VueJS)

https://trustedbhc.com/ (Laravel web Application)

https://ghanathoracicsociety.com/ (Laravel web Application, VueJS)

https://calvarypcgohio.org (Laravel Web Application, VueJS)

https://akomacare.org (Laravel Web Application, VueJS)

https://www.ghapp.bisa.com.gh (Laravel Web Application, VueJS)

https://www.wowlogbook.com (Laravel Web Application, VueJS)

https://www.ofwafrica.org (Laravel Web Application, VueJS))

https://www.apexhealthghana.com/ (Laravel Web Application, VueJS)

https://lotwatcass.app (Multi-Tenant Web Application) Toilet Service

Management System https://ctgmoss.com (Multi-Tenant Web

Application) Toilet Service Management System